The fairest of them all...the funniest of them all!
Mary Poppins is a comedy, family, fantasy film directed by Robert Stevenson.
In turn of the century London, a magical nanny employs music and adventure to
help two neglected children become closer to their father.
Mary Poppins, played by Julie Andrews.
Bert / Mr. Dawes Sr., played by Dick Van Dyke.
Mr. Banks, played by David Tomlinson.
Mrs. Banks, played by Glynis Johns.
Ellen, played by Hermione Baddeley.
Jane Banks, played by Karen Dotrice.
Mary Poppins is a 1964 American live-action animated musical fantasy comedy film directed by Robert
Stevenson and produced by Walt Disney, with songs written and composed by the Sherman Brothers.
The screenplay is by Bill Walsh and Don DaGradi, based on P.
Travers's book series Mary Poppins.
The film, which combines live-action and animation, stars Julie Andrews, in her feature film debut, as Mary Poppins, who
visits a dysfunctional family in London and employs her unique brand of lifestyle to improve the family's dynamic.
Dick Van Dyke, David Tomlinson, and Glynis Johns
are featured in supporting roles.
The film was shot entirely at the Walt Disney Studios in Burbank,
California, using painted London background scenes.
Mary Poppins was released on August 27, 1964, to universal critical acclaim and commercial
success, earning $44 million in theatrical rentals in its original run.
It became the highest-grossing film of 1964 in the United States, and at the
time of its release became Disney's highest-grossing film.
During its theatrical lifetime, it grossed over $103 million worldwide.
It received a total of thirteen Academy Award nominations—a record for any film released by Walt Disney Studios—including Best Picture, and won five: Best
Actress for Andrews, Best Film Editing, Best Original Music Score, Best Visual Effects, and Best Original Song for "Chim Chim Cher-ee".
In 2013, it was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the Library of Congress as being
"culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant."
A biographical drama based on the making of the film, Saving Mr.
Banks, was released in 2013.
A sequel to the original film, Mary Poppins Returns, was released in 2018.
The film explores themes of banker, london, england, sibling
relationship, based on novel or book, parent child relationship.
The tone is lighthearted.